I'd like to encourage us to start asking ourselves why. Like, you know, when you're a kid and
everything is why, why, why? Bring that back. Start asking yourself why about yourself. Like
when you are about to react to something, ask yourself, why am I reacting that way?
When you have a strong feeling or a strong thought about something, ask yourself,
why do I have that thought? When you decide that you're going to do an action, ask yourself,
why am I doing that action? But like really ask yourself and be honest with yourself.
I'm doing it because my feelings were hurt. I'm doing it because I'm petty. I'm doing it because
they made me feel a way. And so I want them to feel a way. Those are the cats.
Um, and then ask yourself if you think that's really useful because we can't actually challenge
the systems that are in place. If we can't even challenge ourselves, if we won't even admit to
ourselves when we're being jealous, if we want to admit to ourselves when we're being petty,
if we won't admit to ourselves when we're projecting and acting out, if we won't admit
to ourselves when we're being selfish, et cetera. And listen, you can be any of those things and
still course correct, right? It's not like if I am one of those things, then I am a bad person.
I don't deserve anything in the world. And that's what I think people are really afraid of and why
they don't ask themselves about themselves. But if we're not going to ask ourselves about ourselves,
we're not going to ask our environment. We're not going to ask our society. We're not going to ask
our systems about themselves and thus they will continue to control us. And the irony of that
is that they control us more than we control ourselves. Something to think about. Talk to your
teens about it. By the way, it's sweater season and I am not playing with y'all ever. Ralph! Houston,
New Orleans, Dallas, Atlanta, my What Would the Ancestors Say mission-driven book tour is coming your way.
Come on out, be in community, buy a book and get it signed. RSVP at amandaseals.com.